Priyono Santosa

Full Stack Developer | Digital Media Professional

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

More than 7 years take part in the digital marketing industry and worked for various business owners, startups, companies and non-profit organizations around South East Asia.



As a full stack developer, I have a strong multidisciplinary background and proven work on content strategy and creation, UI/UX research and design, web and CMS development, SEO and SEM, social media marketing, e-commerce optimization and data visualization.

In terms of leadership skills, I have more than 5 years experience building teams from scratch, screening the best developer talent around the country, coaching Agile and Scrum Framework materials, direct and maintaining their performance on a daily basis with tools such as Trello, Slack, JIRA and other Agile project management software.

KEY SKILLS

- Project Planning and Budgeting
- Content Strategy & Creation
- User Experience (UX) Research
- User Interface (UI) Design
- Full Stack Website Development
- System Administrator/ DevOps
- Search Engine Optimization
- App Store Optimization
- Digital Marketing
- Data Visualization & Analytical
- Website Performance Monitoring
- Scrum Master/ Agile
- Product Development
- Project Management

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Operating System: Mac, Linux, Windows
- Web Server: Nginx, Centos, Apache
- Cloud: Google Cloud Platform, Amazon Web Services, Digital Ocean
- Serverless: Vercel, Netlify
- Database: SQL, MongoDb
- Programming: PHP, Vanilla Javascript, NodeJS, ReactJS, VueJs, Python, Java, R Language
- Frameworks: Laravel, Codeigniter, NuxtJs, NextJs,
- Traditional CMS: WordPress, Magento, Drupal
- Headless CMS: Strapi, Directus, CrafterCMS
- Version Control System: Gitlab, Github, Bitbucket
- Google/ SEO: GA4, Search Console, Google Tag Manager, Semrush, Ahrefs
- Social Media: Fanpage Karma, Falcon, Buffer, Hootsuite, IFTTT
- Data Visualization/ Science: Google Data Studio, PowerBI, Tableau, R Studio
- Multimedia Editing: Adobe Premier, Kdenlive, Audacity
- Graphic Design: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, GIMP, Inkscape
- Agile/ Scrum: Trello, Pivotal Tracker, Slack

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Honorable Judge in Indonesia Website Awards 2021 by Exabytes Indonesia Issued Mar 2022

Click to Show Credential

WORKING EXPERIENCE

LEVERATE GROUP - Jakarta, Indonesia

2021 - Present

Web Development Director

- Working directly with Stakeholders, CEO and Managing Director to build 5+ new business ideas on digital media industry in South East Asia region
- Execute new website, SEO and ASO business plan to run inhouse and handling 20+ projects in last two years
- Lead 3 team members including UI/ UX Designer, Senior Web Developer and SEO
 Specialist daily work to higher levels of maturity each of their discipline skills
- Direct and coach team by running 4+ Scrum events on monthly basis
- Provide team performance report on weekly basis and improve team productivity by running and Agile Methods using Pivotal Tracker and Slack in last two years
- Collaborate with Business Development team and winning incoming pitch from brands and corporate clients such as Bank Rakyat Indonesia, BMW, Philip Morris International, Superbank etc

INDODAX - Jakarta, Indonesia

2020 - 2021

Senior Web Developer

- Working directly with General Manager and former team to create new services under Indodax platform, named Bitcoin.co.id
- Collaborate with +5 division from Indodax original team including backend, SEO, blockchain, digital marketing, etc.
- Integrate Bitcoin.co.id with existing Indodax technology stack and launched it under 6 months development

VERY - Jakarta, Indonesia

2018 - 2020

Senior Web Developer

- Working directly with Stakeholder and Director and turn our business from a newcomer remote-work-from-starbucks agency that consist 2 people into creative office based agency in South Jakarta with 50+ employee
- Lead 3 team web development members including frontend developer, backend developer and web admin daily work to handle workload from 10+ initial projects
- Using trello as our project management tools and ensure 100% task delivered from each member by helping them coding directly

RIPSTORE.ASIA - Bandung, Indonesia

2014 - 2018

Web Developer & Founder

- Founded a commercial services in web development, hosting services, content creation, data analyst and digital campaign as a freelance based work
- Lead and maintain 10+ freelancer across Indonesia to handle job request from clients
- Running 200+ projects in 4 years including clients from Indonesia, Malaysia, Singapore, Hong Kong etc.

equalBright Education School - Bandung, Indonesia

2012 - 2014

Web Developer & System Administrator

 Junior school based in Bandung that offers multiple intelligence curriculum based on Information and Communication Technologies standards. As a Web Developer and System Administrator, I manage school server and website, computer networks, hardware and software, develop database software for students and teachers, regular maintenance and computer troubleshooting.

Nusa Cipta Teknologi – Bandung, Indonesia

2010 - 2012

Junior Web Developer

• IT Company based in Bandung that offers web and mobile apps development. As a Junior Web Programmer, I am responsible for developing websites and content management systems using PHP Framework and content management systems for client needs.

STARTUPS/PROJECT-BASED EXPERIENCE

Posberitakota.com

2016 - Present

Web Developer & Founder

Startup media company based in Bekasi. This is my personal project with my father Agus Santosa – known as a senior journalist in Jakarta. As a Business Intelligence I am responsible for creating basic concepts, server and website development, advertisement, and expanding networks with other media stakeholders in Indonesia. We are now looking for investors to join our project.

Algoritma Data Science Academy

Aug 2018 - Oct 2018

Web Developer & Data Science Student

Data science academy and training based in Jakarta. As a Web Developer, I am responsible for developing Algoritma's Online Learning Management System. I also followed Data Visualization class for 3 months at Block71 Jakarta held by Algoritma.

Disorder Zine 2014 – 2017

Web Developer & Senior Content Writer

Music magazine based in Jakarta. As a Senior Editor and Web Developer, I am responsible for creating magazine basic concepts, server and website development, content curation, and expanding network with other music journalists in Indonesia.

Jakartabeat.net 2011 – 2017

Web Developer & Senior Content Writer

Online Syndication Magazine that publishes articles from many contributors around Indonesia. As a Senior Editor and Web Developer, I am responsible for creating magazine basic concepts, server and website development, content curation, and expanding network with other music journalists in Indonesia.

EDUCATION

Institut Ilmu Sosial dan Ilmu Politik IISIP Jakarta	2000 - 2008
Journalism Bachelor Degree	
SMAN 71 Jakarta	1997 - 2000
SMPN 117 Jakarta	1997 - 1994

PERSONAL DATA

Full Name : Priyono Santosa

Nick Name : Priyo

City/ Date of Birth : Jakarta/ July 31, 1982

Religion : Moslem
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Indonesia

Full Address : Jalan Kalibata Tengah XVI No 26 RT 11/03, Kalibata

Pancoran, Jakarta Selatan, Indonesia 12740

Phone :+628881536856

E-mail : priyonosantosa.id@gmail.com

Personal Website : <u>www.themeprys.com</u>